我想我在
One of the the thing that
教学勇气运动中
I guess I'm most devoted to
最执着的事情之一
in the courage to teach movement
就是创造一种社区形式，
is to create a form of community
其中有几条基本规则。
in which there are several basic ground rules.
我经常这样总结，
And the way I often sum them up is
在这个社区里，没有修正,
in this community there will be no fixing,
没有拯救,
there will be no saving,
没有建议,
there will be no advising,
没有纠正。
there will be no settings straight.
如果你排除掉这四件事情,
Now if you eliminate those four things,
我们大多数人都不清楚
most of us haven't got the foggiest
该如何处理彼此之间的关系，
idea what to do with one another,
因为我们觉得我们是在
because we feel somehow we're in the
修正、建议、拯救和纠正的事情。
business of fixing, advising, saving and setting straight.
但是当你创建一个
But when you create a community
禁止这些行为的社区时，
in which those behaviors are outlawed,
你就为人们创造了巨大的解放，
you create enormous liberation for people
让他们真正地探索自己的真相是什么。
to really explore what their truth is.
这并不意味着善意的忽视,
This doesn't mean benign neglect,
也不意味着我在
it doesn't mean that I said
你说话或说你的真相时，
while you're talking or saying your truth
盯着窗外看。
and stare out the window.
我与你交互，听你说话，
I'm engaged with you, I listen to you,
我试着接受你所说的一切。
I try to receive what you're saying.
我可能想问你一个
And I may want to ask you
关于它的诚实的开放性问题：
an honest open question about it:
“是什么导致你说出你刚才所说的话？”，
what leads you to say what you just said
或者说，“你的生活中哪来的这些？”，
or where does that come from in your life
或者说，“你刚才所说的话
or what implications do you think
对你的生活有什么影响？”
what you've just said has for your life.
像我们在教学勇气运动中一样，
It's very important to work as we do
如何提出诚实的开放性问题
in this courage to teach movement
是非常重要的工作。
on how to ask honest open questions.
因为我们事实上被训练去问一些问题，
Because we are trained in fact to ask questions
这些问题是我们变相的
that our speeches in disguise
演说或建议和变相的修正。
or advices and fixes in disguise.
因此，如果你说了一些
So if you say something that about
关于你正在挣扎的问题，
an issue you're struggling with,
而我看着你说:
and I look at you and say:
“你有没有想过去看心理医生?”
"Have you thought about seeing a therapist?",
这就不是一个诚实的开放性问题。
that's not an honest open questions.
我坐在这里想,
I'm sitting here thinking,
她应该去看心理医生。
she ought to see a therapist.
对于这样一个问题，我所做的是
And what I do with a question like that is
试图在提问的掩护下
to try to fix you or save you
修正你或拯救你。
under the cover of asking a question.
像这样的问题，你有没有想过
Questions like that have you thought about seeing
看心理医生，或者你看不出来这是你母亲的问题吗，
a therapist or can't you see it's your mother
或者这里有一本你应该读的书，
or here's a book you ought to read,
为什么你还没有读。
why haven't you read it yet.
这些问题有很大的力量来关闭灵魂，
Those questions have great power to shut down the soul,
关闭内心老师的声音。
to shut down the voice of the inner teacher.
诚实的开放性问题会邀请
Honest open questions invite
内心的声音进行更充分的表达。
that inner voice into fuller expression.
我所说的诚实的问题是指，
By an honest question I mean
当我问这个问题时，我不是坐在这里
I'm not sitting here when I ask it
想知道这个问题的正确答案，
thinking I know the right answer to this
我当然希望他或她能给我答案。
and I sure hope that he or she gives it to me.
我所说的开放性问题是指，
And by an open question I mean
它不会把你逼到角落，
one that doesn't back you into a corner
我要么提出解决方案修正，
where I'm proposing either the fix or
要么提出修正的方向，
the direction of a fix and you have to
如果你想保住自己的地盘，你必须就得跟我对着干。
kind of fight against me if you want to hold your own turf.
这是一门巨大的艺术。
It's an enormous art.
但对我来说，它与我对人类
But it is for me related to my
灵魂的理解有关。
understanding of the human soul.
我有一个非常生动的
I have a very vivid formini image of
关于人类灵魂的形象。
what the human soul is like.
我认为人类的灵魂就像野生动物。
I think the human soul is exactly like a wild animal.
我们知道野生动物非常机智，
We know that wild animals are very resourceful,
适应能力很强,
they're very resilient,
很精明,
they're very savvy,
他们知道如何在艰难的地方生存。
they know how to survive in tough places.
而所有这些都是人类灵魂的真实写照，
And all of that is true of the human soul,
如果不是这样的话，在任何一个房间
if it weren't true, there's a whole bunch of people
都有一大堆人，如果他们没有这种足智多谋的精神
in any room who wouldn't be here today,
可以依靠的话，他们今天就不会在这里了。
if they hadn't had that resourcefulness to fall back on.
但也像野生动物一样，
But also like a wild animal,
人类的灵魂本质上是害羞的。
the human soul is essentially shy.
我们知道，如果我们想看野生动物,
We know that if we want to see a wild animal,
我们在这个世界上最不应该做的事情
the last thing in the world we should do
就是冲进树林里大喊大叫，
is to go crashing into the woods screaming
让其出来。
and yelling for the thing to come out.
我们可以在接下来的50年里这样做，
We can do that for the next 50 years
但永远不会看到我们寻找的东西。
and never see the thing we seek.
我们也知道，如果我们
We also know that if we will walk
悄悄地走进树林，
into the woods quietly,
坐在树根上,
sit at the base of a tree,
和大地一起呼吸一两个小时,
breathe with the earth for an hour or two,
也许我们要找的东西
it may well be that the thing we seek
将会出现，
is going to put in an appearance,
那只野生动物会让自己了解到，
that wild animal will make itself known
因为这个地方很安全。
because the space feels safe.
我们至少会从眼角
And we will at least catch a glimpse
瞥到一瞥那灵魂，
out of the corner of our eye and
我们一生都不会忘记那一瞥。
all our lives we will never forget that glimpse.
在教学勇气团体中,
The courage to teach groups,
我们为之工作的社区形式，
the form of community that we're working for there
就像走进森林,
is exactly like walking into the woods,
彼此安静地坐在树根下，
sitting quietly at the base of the tree with each other
等待灵魂出场的
and waiting for that precious moment
那个珍贵时刻。
when the soul puts in an appearance.
当灵魂出现时，以完全和
And when it does, treating it with utter and
无条件的尊重对待k，让k找到自己的声音。
unconditional respect and letting it find its own voice.